[{"id": "5909d062bb53d1af658864fb", "question": "What year was the computer worm, \"Father Christmas\", released into the world?", "answer": "1988", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ecc", "question": "What baseball player is Santiago's hero in \"The Old Man and the Sea\"?", "answer": "Joe DiMaggio", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab3a", "question": "What is the capital of Colorado?", "answer": "Denver", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f566a133a95c66dc4fe764", "question": "Germany's World War I allies were Austria-Hungary, Bulgaria, and which empire?", "answer": "Ottoman Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aede", "question": "In which city was Joan of Arc burnt to death?", "answer": "Rouen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee8", "question": "Which battle saw the final defeat of the Jacobites in 1746?", "answer": "Battle of Culloden", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba99", "question": "Where did former NFL star Joe Montana play college football?", "answer": "Notre Dame", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecdb35ec223966ae8f88f1", "question": "In \"Raiders of the Lost Ark,\" what chases Indy out of the Temple of the Chachapoyan Warriors?", "answer": "A giant rolling boulder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133961a", "question": "The \"Sacred Order of the Stonecutters\" was a fictional club in which TV show?", "answer": "The Simpsons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015eaf2fe83fe1f2a824bf6", "question": "Which Native American tribe took part in the first Thanksgiving feast?", "answer": "Wampanoag", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e3", "question": "What is kept in a ship's binnacle?", "answer": "Compass", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fede2266ce05a3942286dcd", "question": "\"Santa Baby\" contributed to which singer\u2019s fame?", "answer": "Eartha Kitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c993fbde8045e48466ef", "question": "What is a group of jelly fish called?", "answer": "A smack", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600cc8b16de0eb824d4052fe", "question": "Which U.S. state named the cherry as its official state fruit?", "answer": "Utah -- A 1997 school class campaigned on behalf of cherries, an important crop in Utah, and got the nod from state legislators.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c54d", "question": "Kimberlite contains what precious stone?", "answer": "Diamond", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e9", "question": "How many calories do the US Postal Service stamps contain?", "answer": "One-tenth of a calorie", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a506", "question": "Hellas is the local name for which country?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ab1b3234fda37788a9a1dc0", "question": "What is the basis for guacamole?", "answer": "Avocado", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b393", "question": "Who was the 35th President of the US?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e6bd51fb6c85e9e634ff66", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Antimony?", "answer": "Sb", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339254", "question": "Who was the first character Johnny Depp portrayed in more than one movie?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe3ea2d38e4e5d4832e6313", "question": "What airline owned the 747 blown up by a terrorist bomb over Lockerbie, Scotland in 1988?", "answer": "PanAm", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c4b5fbde8045e48466a0", "question": "What does the African dung beetle use to navigate at night?", "answer": "The Milky Way -- The only animal known to navigate using the Milky Way, they can move objects that are 50 times their weight.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a4", "question": "Mt. Blanc is the highest peak in what mountain range?", "answer": "The Alps", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399bd", "question": "What duo\u2019s first names were Don and Phil?", "answer": "The Everly Brothers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc1abec223966ae8f886c", "question": "Makeup artist Joanna Balkin says she needed 40 bottles of sunscreen per month to protect what 1990s TV show\u2019s cast from sunburns?", "answer": "\"Baywatch\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe2583f658e585fda9cfa3e", "question": "Black Forest cake originates from which country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa5", "question": "What was the nickname of the Spice Girls singer Geri Halliwell?", "answer": "Ginger Spice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab1b7fbaab681b0929219a", "question": "What is BMW's name short for?", "answer": "Bayerische Motoren Werke", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d1", "question": "What is the capital of New Mexico?", "answer": "Santa Fe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdc143b469bb8041d07a085", "question": "Which U.S. best-selling wine is often referred to as \"over-oaked\" and \"not food-friendly\"?", "answer": "Chardonnay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b7ff9513a3a814d89068c53", "question": "What is Ethiopia's official language?", "answer": "Amharic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d06d97870e6f05ba600859", "question": "Who directed the 1986 film \"The Fly\"?", "answer": "David Cronenberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf0", "question": "What European conflict lasted 116 years?", "answer": "The Hundred Years War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a49", "question": "What was the real first name of the jazz performer Duke Ellington?", "answer": "Edward", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339247", "question": "What is the stage name of Gordon Matthew Thomas Sumner?", "answer": "Sting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfa2", "question": "What are wrapped in bacon to make the dish \"Angels on Horseback\"?", "answer": "Oysters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b89", "question": "What is the number of thieves that Alibaba had?", "answer": "40", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398b9", "question": "What comedic duo starred in the movie \"Stir Crazy\"?", "answer": "Gene Wilder and Richard Pryor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ab7", "question": "In the movie \"Home Alone\" what nickname did the burglars bestow upon themselves?", "answer": "The Wet Bandits", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af3b", "question": "Who was the first Republican US president?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c41b", "question": "What is the common word for a weight suspended from a pivot that can move freely?", "answer": "A pendulum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339788", "question": "How many copies must a recording sell to be designated multi-platinum?", "answer": "2 million", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049d91cf93664eb10486ae", "question": "The plane carrying what country\u2019s national rugby team crashed on Friday, October 13, 1972?", "answer": "Uruguay\u2019s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa9", "question": "Who wrote The Angel Doll: A Christmas Story in 1996?", "answer": "Jerry Bledsoe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389ca", "question": "What decade was Agatha Christie's \"Murder on the Orient Express\" set in?", "answer": "The 1920s", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b894", "question": "In which track and field event do athletes throw a spear?", "answer": "Javelin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1f8", "question": "Who chose her new name in 1953 to honor a Danish surgeon named Christian Hamburger?", "answer": "Christine Jorgensen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6c9", "question": "What state is nicknamed the \"Beehive State\"?", "answer": "Utah", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff2599031a458464a93c46d", "question": "In the US South, ground hominy is more popularly know as what?", "answer": "Grits", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4d1", "question": "Which two numbers are used in the binary system?", "answer": "Zero and one", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbf", "question": "Which two public figures were assassinated in the United States in 1968?", "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr. and Robert Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339655", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who invented the drink \"The Flaming Moe\"?", "answer": "Homer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b50201dd7bf43be5e7cb", "question": "What is the main ingredient in the British dish laverbread?", "answer": "Seaweed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133966a", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", which character has a pacemaker?", "answer": "Krusty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab47", "question": "Mogadishu is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Somalia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133901d", "question": "Sidney Paget is famous for creating the visual image of which literary character?", "answer": "Sherlock Holmes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b953", "question": "In a game of basketball, how many players are on the court at one time?", "answer": "Ten", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a11", "question": "On the TV show \"The West Wing\", Jed Bartlett was governor of which state before being elected president?", "answer": "New Hampshire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600241ec4be4723ccac2217f", "question": "Which author wrote the spy novel \"Tinker, Tailor, Soldier, Spy\"?", "answer": "John Le Carre", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c859", "question": "What are the only two consecutive prime numbers?", "answer": "2 and 3", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ad7ec5ab24f84e0b9f9ffe6", "question": "Which sport was invented by Dr. James Naismith in 1891?", "answer": "Basketball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338934", "question": "Approximately how many lines is \"Beowulf\", the longest Old English manuscript?", "answer": "Over 3,000", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "590682ceff9c0647b50a80a0", "question": "Who won the 2016 Oscar for Best Actor?", "answer": "Leonardo DiCaprio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60160173fe83fe1f2a824c5f", "question": "According to a famous Polish legend, which creature made a blanket to keep baby Jesus warm?", "answer": "A spider, which is why Poles have a great reverence for spiders.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c81afbde8045e48466cf", "question": "What are the tiny air sacs in the lungs called?", "answer": "Alveoli", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aefb", "question": "What American outlaw went by such names as Kid Antrim, Henry McCarty and William Bonney?", "answer": "Billy the Kid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d4e", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"The Girl in the Kremlin\"?", "answer": "Natalie Darryl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339613", "question": "What sport was featured in the 1985 movie \"Vision Quest\"?", "answer": "Wrestling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600b88741d8c1817608d53f3", "question": "From which part of a pig do we get ham?", "answer": "Hind leg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b372dc1c3f17ccc40c8e28", "question": "Rodney Dangerfield, Phil LaMarr and Randy Quaid starred in which 2005 film?", "answer": "Back by Midnight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b83a", "question": "What food got its name by the way it hung in bunches like grapes?", "answer": "Grapefruit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e3f35d5cb9e8bda6821363", "question": "What ancient city did Swiss explorer Johann Ludwig Burckhardt introduce to the Western world in 1812?", "answer": "Petra", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cad", "question": "What 2002 movie was developed under the title \"Surf Girls of Maui\"?", "answer": "Blue Crush", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea37f3ff048f679a45ab1e", "question": "What is it called when you make light change direction by passing it through a lens?", "answer": "Refraction", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3e9", "question": "What year did the Republic of South Sudan gain its independence?", "answer": "2011", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a20c20565ad31a57c7aa", "question": "Who gave the first known diamond engagement ring?", "answer": "Archduke Maximilian of Austria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6fb", "question": "Annapolis is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c98", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Stuckeyville, Ohio?", "answer": "Ed", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c3", "question": "Which politician was given the nickname Tarzan?", "answer": "Michael Heseltine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe93b8e6bd93ce3a4e5f6a4", "question": "What did Theodoric of Freiberg correctly explain?", "answer": "Rainbow phenomenon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59049a0bcf93664eb1048697", "question": "The Queensland nut is another name for what nut?", "answer": "Macadamia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c1de877e98cb9777897f", "question": "What was the first cave in the world to be designated a national park?", "answer": "Wind Cave", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133983a", "question": "Who won a Grammy Award for his album \"Come Dance With Me\"?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c77f", "question": "The Moon's name is derived from the Latin word meaning what?", "answer": "Month", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf9", "question": "What was the first building in the world to have more than 100 floors?", "answer": "Empire State Building", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdbb", "question": "What animal was used in British coal mines until being phased out in 1986?", "answer": "Canaries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bfdff4ab668d7dfe168b5b6", "question": "What were the dolls in the novel \"Valley of the Dolls\"?", "answer": "Pills/Drugs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59523dfa736d4be723796b49", "question": "What does the \"Calgary Stampede\" bills itself as?", "answer": "The Greatest Outdoor Show on Earth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf4c", "question": "Which English club was formed as Ardwick FC?", "answer": "Manchester United", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a6e", "question": "Who wrote the book \"The Electric Kool-Aid Acid Test\"?", "answer": "Tom Wolfe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea40f3ff048f679a45ab6c", "question": "Who discovered that a moving magnet generates electric current known as electromagnetic induction?", "answer": "Michael Faraday", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c885", "question": "How many arms does a squid have?", "answer": "Ten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b9", "question": "What was the first music video that aired on MTV in 1981?", "answer": "Video Killed the Radio Star", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a9", "question": "Who had the job of eliminating maverick androids?", "answer": "Blade runners", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391df", "question": "Who played Mr. Pink in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Steve Buscemi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5977442d284458f1d785442d", "question": "The original name of New York City was what?", "answer": "New Amsterdam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b0", "question": "Who played the role of Andy Dufresne in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Tim Robbins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df0", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"catamaran\"?", "answer": "Tamil", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ed", "question": "What is the inflammation of the stomach and small intestine called?", "answer": "Gastroenteritis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c77cf8024f0f7a362efd54e", "question": "In \"The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time\", what are the names of the six races?", "answer": "Hylian, Kokiri, Goron, Zora, Gerudo, Shiekah.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab4f", "question": "What city is the Lighthouse of Alexandria located in?", "answer": "Pharos", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cd809e347d002c297e4c6", "question": "In Greek mythology, who flew too close to the Sun?", "answer": "Icarus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65f211f3c0ead6880d635", "question": "Which President of South Africa ordered Nelson Mandela\u2019s release from prison?", "answer": "De Klerk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f0", "question": "Which continent is the home of the tsetse fly?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b057", "question": "Who was Michael Dukakis\u2019s Vice-Presidential running mate in the 1988 US Presidential election?", "answer": "Lloyd Bentsen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391bc", "question": "What is the name of the studio founded by Sidney Poitier, Barbra Streisand and Paul Newman in 1969?", "answer": "First Artists", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aca1", "question": "What is the name of the first nuclear-powered submarine?", "answer": "USS Nautilus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b22501dd7bf43be5e79a", "question": "Talking to people who agree with you is like doing what?", "answer": "Preaching to the choir", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ae", "question": "What is the largest joint in the body?", "answer": "The knee joint", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c78a", "question": "What is the chemical formula for ozone?", "answer": "O3", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e72cc4bd0874f1a5e2d1c23", "question": "Who was the first European explorer under the flag of England to reach North America?", "answer": "John Cabot", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9b937364247bf200fb889", "question": "Who made the song \"A Boy Named Sue\" popular in 1969?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba1", "question": "What famous movie actor got his start playing the first openly gay nationally broadcast TV character, in the late 1970's?", "answer": "Billy Crystal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523d84736d4be723796b43", "question": "For what period of time is the Governor General of Canada appointed?", "answer": "Unfixed", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d33", "question": "What surgeon on the TV show ER shares his name with a \"Warlord of Mars\" created by Edgar Rice Burroughs?", "answer": "John Carter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c957", "question": "Approximately how many miles is an Astronomical Unit?", "answer": "93 million", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4af249076251badbeabe", "question": "Ruby Bridges became the first Black student to do what?", "answer": "At six-years-old, Ruby Bridges was the first Black child to be integrated into an all-white school in New Orleans in 1960.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febba037e83c707845b2142", "question": "What is the object that opposing players must destroy in order to win at \"League of Legends\"?", "answer": "Nexus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76b9deec85e375820b2c5", "question": "Where is smashing plates against your friends\u2019 door a New Year\u2019s Eve custom?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5bf", "question": "Which French designer was the heir to a fertilizer fortune?", "answer": "Christian Dior", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4b0", "question": "Balsam, Fraser, and Douglas are all types of what?", "answer": "Firs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dde", "question": "What two British politicians of the 1960s are mentioned by George Harrison in \"Taxman\"?", "answer": "Harold Wilson and Edward Heath", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b99", "question": "In 2000, who became the first Asian woman to host \"Saturday Night Live\"?", "answer": "Lucy Liu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133990d", "question": "What fictitious planet did ALF claim to be an alien from?", "answer": "Melmac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66044a5bfecdd737e0832", "question": "What was the first pizza chain in the United States?", "answer": "Pizza Hut", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339982", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who was Barney's high school sweetheart?", "answer": "Chloe Talbot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133890f", "question": "Who wrote \"Treasure Island\"?", "answer": "Robert Louis Stevenson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594a62f72ebb971c1417fb95", "question": "The \"Turbot War\" was a fishing dispute between Spain and what other country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a50c", "question": "The Hagia Sophia is located in what country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600cc8a06de0eb824d4052fd", "question": "\"The Blue House\" is the official residence of the leader of what country?", "answer": "South Korea -- Originally known as \"Gyeongmudae\", the name was changed in 1960 to \"Cheong Wa Dae\", meaning blue house.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed6", "question": "What colour is chablis?\u00a0", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ef", "question": "What is added to cachaca to make a Caipirinha?", "answer": "Sugar and lime", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b752", "question": "Whose ear did Mike Tyson bite in a 1997 fight dubbed \"The Sound and the Fury\"?", "answer": "Evander Holyfield's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c963", "question": "Parr, Smolt and Grilse are lifecycle stages for what fish?", "answer": "Salmon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c60f", "question": "What is the study of space called?", "answer": "Astronomy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c495", "question": "What vitamin group is mostly required for blood coagulation?", "answer": "Vitamin K", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4c4", "question": "What term for a rocket's propulsive force is calculated by multiplying its exhaust velocity by the burn rate of its fuel?", "answer": "Thrust", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339975", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Lenny's last name?", "answer": "Leonard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cde", "question": "What does Marvel Comics character Howard the Duck often have in his mouth?", "answer": "A cigar", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c7", "question": "In the game \"Plants vs Zombies\", what do players collect as currency to buy plants?", "answer": "Sunlight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a83b90aac110e416708c", "question": "Who said \"He that drinks his cider alone, let him catch his horse alone.\"?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae99", "question": "Established in 1607, what settlement was founded by John Smith in Virginia?", "answer": "Jamestown", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e6", "question": "What year was the Amazon Kindle Fire first introduced?", "answer": "2011", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a771", "question": "Which US state is home to a city called Truth or Consequences?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2fb", "question": "In which 1966 film did Stephen Boyd star alongside Raquel Welch?", "answer": "Fantastic Voyage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7af", "question": "The strait which connects the East China Sea with the South China Sea is named for what island nation?", "answer": "Taiwan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abb0", "question": "Which US coast is the state of Maryland located on?", "answer": "East", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973c", "question": "Who won an Oscar for the theme song from the movie \"Shaft\"?", "answer": "Isaac Hayes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f3", "question": "What is Tchaikovsky's ballet \"Le Lac des Cygnes\" commonly called?", "answer": "Swan Lake", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec3", "question": "Who created the New Model Army?", "answer": "Oliver Cromwell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd1", "question": "Who was the beautiful youth loved by the Greek goddess Aphrodite?", "answer": "Adonis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59523fff736d4be723796b5d", "question": "Which city became the first capital of the Province of Canada in 1841?", "answer": "Kingston, Ontario", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febab647e83c707845b20e8", "question": "Which planet has moons named Hippocamp and Proteus?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff51247ff04d658268c92ce", "question": "Cleopatra represented herself as the reincarnation of what Egyptian goddess?", "answer": "Cleopatra represented herself as the reincarnation of the Egyptian goddess\u00a0Isis.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b36d", "question": "Which country was the first to allow women to vote in 1893?\u00a0", "answer": "New Zealand\u00a0", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda8", "question": "What team's fans were inspired by the Rally Monkey?", "answer": "The Anaheim Angels", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d23", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"National Velvet\"?", "answer": "Horse racing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339805", "question": "What band name did Nick Rhodes, John Taylor, Simon Le Bon, Roger Taylor and Andy Taylor take?", "answer": "Duran Duran", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c90d3ce52800b05cac20f19", "question": "Approximately, how many days is the rotation period of Venus?", "answer": "243 days", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a698", "question": "Xerox was founded in 1906 In what U.S. City?", "answer": "Rochester, New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59dece53ea2747c8aff16d16", "question": "What is Joey's favourite food in the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Sandwiches", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c598", "question": "What tree gives us prunes?", "answer": "The plum tree", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fbaead10738315b1fb74e2b", "question": "Diamondback and Timber are types of what animal?", "answer": "Rattlesnakes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd4", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"tsunami\"?", "answer": "Japanese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae95", "question": "Where did Davy Crockett die?", "answer": "The Alamo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d118174fea7fe947a22281", "question": "What metal has the chemical symbol Pb?", "answer": "Lead", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59029fe7cad1ec93f27df765", "question": "What country does the cappuccino originate from?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8b60ec223966ae8f883c", "question": "Lady Gaga derived her stage name from a song performed by which legendary band?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd536e347d002c297e4b6", "question": "Which book did James Fenimore Cooper publish in 1826 that was later made into a movie, starring Daniel Day-Lewis?", "answer": "The Last of the Mohicans", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eb17cf83302ff91e464a8", "question": "What cartoon by Mike Judge is the 1999 film \"Office Space\" based on?", "answer": "Milton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a846", "question": "The Gulf of Oman connects the Persian Gulf with what sea?", "answer": "Arabian Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b11e", "question": "Who was the second US President to appear on the face of a US coin?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea8078ff048f679a45ac19", "question": "What extinct animal was the ancestor of cattle?", "answer": "Auroch", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f9f3f3eaf848b908361b86b", "question": "What amusement ride was first ridden in 1893 at the World's Columbian Exposition in Chicago?", "answer": "The Ferris Wheel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b92f", "question": "What yard line must a football team drive to, to reach the \"red zone\"?", "answer": "The 20", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecda1bec223966ae8f88e6", "question": "What character in \"Monty Python and the Holy Grail\" insists that \"It's just a flesh wound\"?", "answer": "Black Knight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5d", "question": "Clarence Darrow was coaxed out of retirement to defend what famous duo?", "answer": "Leopold & Loeb", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d47103f8e329de4f877897", "question": "What is the brewery featured in the British soap opera \"Coronation Street\"?", "answer": "Newton and Ridley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60121c2b63c99d48cd169b12", "question": "Norman Rockwell painted 323 covers for which magazine?", "answer": "\"Saturday Evening Post\" -- The magazine featured Rockwell\u2019s work from 1916 to 1963.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf34", "question": "In Scotland what was the tawse?", "answer": "Teachers Strap or belt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339939", "question": "What legendary record label was founded by Sam Phillips in 1952?", "answer": "Sun Records", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a94db61d1b4d384d5d672", "question": "Who created Popeye?", "answer": "Elzie Segar", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e2d", "question": "What Greek god, killed by a wild boar, inspired Percy Shelley's elegy for his friend Keats?", "answer": "Adonis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a7f", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Dragon Seed\"?", "answer": "Pearl S. Buck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a6", "question": "What movie starred Mel Gibson as William Wallace?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6644ea5bfecdd737e0853", "question": "Who was the highest-paid TV host in 2018?", "answer": "Judge Judy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399f7", "question": "What R&B singer was backed by \"The Miracles\"?", "answer": "Smokey Robinson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3dbbff048f679a45ab51", "question": "What enzyme is responsible for breaking down starches?", "answer": "Amylase", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e93a6f9d6f11f394a3b2d56", "question": "What is the Star Wars character Emperor Palpatine's first name?", "answer": "Sheev", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ca", "question": "Who played the male lead in the 1947 film \"The Bishop's Wife\"?", "answer": "Cary Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca71", "question": "What term is applied to animals or plants that are not nocturnal?", "answer": "Diurnal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7ccbb877e98cb97778a2a", "question": "Avarua, the capital of the Cook Islands, is located on which South Pacific atoll?", "answer": "Rarotonga", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acaf", "question": "Who became King of Italy in 1804?", "answer": "Napoleon I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339693", "question": "Who played the role of Catwoman in the 1992 movie \"Batman Returns\"?", "answer": "Michelle Pfeiffer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b493e49076251badbeaad", "question": "In 1952, the United States Air Force created Project Blue Book to study what?", "answer": "Unidentified Flying Objects (UFOs)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59008d82cf842fa4c4ba96aa", "question": "In the traditional modern deck of cards, which is the only king without a moustache?", "answer": "King of Hearts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe937526bd93ce3a4e5f66b", "question": "In the weasel family, which marine mammal is the heaviest member?", "answer": "Sea otter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600b86681d8c1817608d53e4", "question": "What does the \"E\" stand for in Chuck E. Cheese?", "answer": "Entertainment (Restaurant founder, Nolan Bushnell, happens to be the founder of Atari.)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad7ebfdb24f84e0b9f9ffe2", "question": "The song \"Honolulu Baby\" was written for which Laurel and Hardy film?", "answer": "Sons of the Desert", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a968", "question": "What East Coast port is the largest US city to share its name with a British county?", "answer": "Norfolk, Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b920", "question": "What do Noodlers catch with their bare hands?", "answer": "Catfish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e2b", "question": "Who is Jamie Lee Curtis' mother?", "answer": "Janet Leigh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7df4ff048f679a45ac03", "question": "Arachnophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Spiders", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec0", "question": "What country's civil war is the setting for the film \"Blood Diamond\"?", "answer": "Sierra Leone's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba3d", "question": "What disease devastated America's population of Elm trees?", "answer": "Dutch Elm Disease", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c70", "question": "Sylvester Stallone was born in which US city?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4b73e06d333868d34d6f8", "question": "Who was the British Navy Minister during World War I?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7736ceec85e375820b307", "question": "Which U.S. state is closest to the Tropic of Cancer?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59008e1ccf842fa4c4ba96af", "question": "Who was radio's \"All-American Boy\"?", "answer": "Jack Armstrong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b856", "question": "What was the first Lifesaver flavor?", "answer": "Pep-O-Mint", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c341", "question": "How many ventricles does the brain have?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b624", "question": "What sign of the zodiac is represented by a bull?", "answer": "Taurus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ff", "question": "Mt. Rainier is one of sixteen volcanoes in the world that is classified as what?", "answer": "A Decade Volcano", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b471", "question": "Which UK politician was given the nickname Tarzan?", "answer": "Michael Heseltine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbaf", "question": "In karate, what color belt is earned just before black?", "answer": "Brown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339acc", "question": "What type of birds are the stars of the 2006 animated film \"Happy Feet\"?", "answer": "Penguins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b589", "question": "What does a Turk call \"Turkish Delight\"?", "answer": "Lokum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f29", "question": "Which band member of The Sex Pistols died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Sid Vicious", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febafef7e83c707845b2101", "question": "What was the first live-stream video on the internet?", "answer": "A garage band performance", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339baf", "question": "What knighted English actor played Gandalf in \"The Lord of the Rings\" film trilogy?", "answer": "Ian McKellan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5e106ce05a3942286e2f", "question": "Which movie\u2019s sequel has the tagline \"Same make. Same model. New mission\"?", "answer": "\"Terminator\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008dcfef4f3bc4a292f861d", "question": "Whose \"Civil Disobedience\" essay inspired Dr. Martin Luther King King. Jr.?", "answer": "Henry David Thoreau (Thoreau wrote it after he was imprisoned for protesting slavery by refusing to pay his poll tax.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d13", "question": "What is Linus and Lucy's last name in \"Peanuts\" comics?", "answer": "Van Pelt", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b452", "question": "Which famed hunter, scout, and showman of the Old West nicknamed his rifle \"Lucretia Borgia\"?", "answer": "Buffalo Bill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff146e2b0ee8c595b6d39c1", "question": "What is the oldest operating Broadway theater?", "answer": "The Lyceum Theater", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339242", "question": "How many friends are featured on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Six", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338abd", "question": "Which art form derives its name from the Greek for \"beauty writing\"?", "answer": "Calligraphy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad7ea57b24f84e0b9f9ffd3", "question": "What is the fear of worms, especially parasitic ones, known as?", "answer": "Scoleciphobia, helminthophobia or vermiphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133942c", "question": "How many roles did Cheech Marin play in the 1996 movie \"From Dusk Till Dawn\"?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133999a", "question": "On what street do TV's \"Desperate Housewives\" live?", "answer": "Wisteria Lane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f1c", "question": "What author created the land of Poictesme?", "answer": "James Branch Cabell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf8", "question": "What J.D. Salinger character never found out where the ducks in Central Park go during the winter?", "answer": "Holden Caulfield", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59523d89736d4be723796b44", "question": "For what period of time is the Governor General of Canada appointed?", "answer": "Unfixed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecce80ec223966ae8f88b0", "question": "Who did not attend the 1977 premiere of \"Star Wars: A New Hope\"?", "answer": "George Lucas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acc5", "question": "How long did New York City's first subway system take to build?", "answer": "Four years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8b8bec223966ae8f883f", "question": "Who does the voice over for Dory from \"Finding Nemo\" and \"Finding Dory\"?", "answer": "Ellen DeGeneres", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a475", "question": "How many states are there in Australia?", "answer": "Six", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f9a", "question": "What character from a pop song wears a screwed-down hairdo and snow-white tan?", "answer": "Ziggy Stardust", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b9b", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Rights of Man\"?", "answer": "Thomas Paine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a05", "question": "What was the first movie adaptation of a Hannibal Lecter novel to feature Anthony Hopkins?", "answer": "The Silence of the Lambs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec89fbec223966ae8f882c", "question": "What company designed the New York Yankees logo?", "answer": "Tiffany & Co.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca86", "question": "What culinary ingredient did Hippolyte M\u00e8ge-Mouri\u00e8s invent?", "answer": "Margarine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921c", "question": "What city did the band U2 form in?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb1beeff497e33de8057919", "question": "How many points did LeBron James score in his very first NBA game?", "answer": "25", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe377f90ada16518afdc04e", "question": "Who was the founder of Cartier?", "answer": "Louis-Frantois Cartier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be0b", "question": "Which two boxing weight classifications are named for animals?", "answer": "Bantamweight and flyweight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a120", "question": "Which year did John Schlesinger receive an Academy Award for directing \"Midnight Cowboy\"?", "answer": "1970", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f6", "question": "What union did Jimmy Hoffa head until his 1975 disappearance?", "answer": "The Teamsters", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4a996e61d1b4d384d5d69a", "question": "What TV network was home to the TV show \"Gunsmoke\"?", "answer": "CBS", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e97", "question": "What movie did the villain Noah Cross appear in?", "answer": "Chinatown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a821", "question": "Botany Bay lies off the coast of what country?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b07f", "question": "How many electoral votes did Gerald Ford get in the \u201976 election?", "answer": "240", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b217", "question": "Who was assassinated by Talmadge Hayer?", "answer": "Malcolm X", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7e7a4b24f84e0b9f9ffbb", "question": "Which is the largest state in Australia\u00a0by land area?", "answer": "Western Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1b3", "question": "What was boxer John L. Sullivan nicknamed?", "answer": "The Boston Strong Boy", "category": "general"}]